Product Management | Strategy | Innovation +1 (215) 252-6186 | mail@vidurbhatnagar.com | www.vidurbhatnagar.com

SUMMARY

Technical product manager, with a successful record of delivering enterprise products, including at my own Healthcare startup. Experienced in customer discovery, analytics, UI/UX, crafting product vision/strategy and leading cross-functional teams through ideation, development & launch.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### **SLALOM LLC**

Product Management Lead

**JAN 2019 - SEP 2019** 

First hire in a new team established to develop SaaS products at a consulting firm and help global teams scale delivery.

- Led a cross-functional team of 5 to **launch a new sales intelligence tool across 5 markets** while conducting user interviews, translating business requirements to technical features and coaching the team on agile delivery.
- Architected a data platform for data ingestion and reporting from multiple sources at SightLife (Slalom's largest non-profit client), where I was **selected in a team of 6 across 300 applicants.**

### **KERITON LLC**

Founder & CEO MAR 2016 - AUG 2018

Launched Keriton while pursuing MS in Robotics at UPenn (on a hackathon winning idea) to help moms, nurses and lactation consultants achieve better outcomes for babies by automating breastmilk management. Eventually, took a leave of absence to run the company full-time as I was granted **extraordinary skills status** by the US government (O1 Visa, EB1 Green Card).

- Raised \$1.6M from top-tier VCs and strategic partners like Penn Medicine, International Blue Cross, etc.
- Conducted design thinking sessions with 25 nurses and 350+ moms to launch a 2-app system which **prevented \$2.5M in HIPAA-errors** at a single site, **decreased expiration of milk by 50%** and **saved nurses' time by 50%**.
- Designed UI mockups for 40+ screens and crafted exceptional user experiences such as the world's first lactation analytics platform with real-time chat and photo-sharing, **helping moms' increase their pumping by 40%**.
- Managed the technology team and architected the SaaS platform 2 apps, 4 products, 40+ workflows, 60+ database tables/views, and 80+ APIs with **zero downtime in 1.5 years** with 99.99% SLAs.
- Closed \$1.1M worth of multi-year B2B contracts, created pre-sales collateral and conducted sales demos.
- Coordinated multiple go-live activities at customers' end, and in one instance trained 150+ nurses in 2 weeks.
- Pitched at numerous events to win **14 national and international awards** like Gold Stevie Startup of the Year, America's Most Unique Small Business, Impact Pediatric SXSW Pitch Competition, etc., resulting in **30+ organic press articles.**

#### **SAP LABS INDIA**

Product Owner & Software Engineer

**FEB 2013 - JUL 2015** 

- As the **Youngest Product Owner (globally)**, I led the charge on enterprise visualizations & dashboards for SAP Cloud for Planning and SAP Lumira. I was responsible for defining roadmaps, building cross-functional consensus, and delivery.
- Created user stories and conducted customer workshops as a Product Management Fellow for SAP Palo Alto team for Stanford's Social Flex Seating - a group-ticketing app.
- Selected as a **Technical Fellow in the Managing Director's office** to develop API services, SQL scripts, and predictive algorithms on SAP HANA (SAP Sports Analytics) that helped a Cricket franchisee in India win back to back championships.
- Developed a novel algorithm for SAP HANA to optimize compression algorithms to achieve an improvement of 75-100% on data access speeds. I was awarded as the **2013 Employee of the Year** (across 4500 employees in India) for this project.

# **ROHITS & CO. (INDIA)**

Freelance Software Engineer

**JUL 2011 - JAN 2013** 

Developed a tool to automate revenue cycle management for SMBs, reducing process time from 30 days to 15 mins.

## **EDUCATION**

### **UNIVERSITY OF PENNSYLVANIA**

2015 - 2016

Candidate for MS in Robotics (Major – Artificial Intelligence)

GPA - 4.0 (on 4)

- A+ grade for a distributed mini-Google search engine (based on the PageRank algorithm) over 1M crawled pages
- 3 awards at PennApps world's largest hackathon 2nd Prize (2015), 2nd Prize (2016), Best Entrepreneurial Hack (2016)

### **JAYPEE INSTITUTE OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY**

2008 - 2013

Dual Degree BS (Computer Science) & MBA (HR)

MBA GPA - 8.9 | BS GPA - 8.5 (on 10)

- 2nd rank (out of 150)
- A+ grade for thesis project on Sign Language to Voice Conversion Gloves
- Government of India scholarship for academic excellence (for 5 years from 2008 2013)

### **SKILLS**

- Product Management Customer Discovery, Feature Prioritization, Roadmaps, GTM and Pricing Strategies
- Full-Stack Development & Cloud Architecture Java, JS, SQL, Angular JS, Ionic, Cordova, React, Node JS, Git, AWS
- Data & Analytics Python, Tableau, PowerBI
- Sales & Marketing Streak, Zoho, Hubspot, MailChimp
- UI/UX Photoshop, Inkscape
- Exceptional interpersonal and communication (written, verbal and presentation) skills
- Strong problem solving, negotiating, conflict resolution and decision-making skills

### **PATENTS & PUBLICATIONS**

•	Visualization of Key Performance Indicator Dependencies (US)	Jun 2017 ( <b>Issued</b> )
•	Optimization Using Statistical Estimation (US/EU)	Apr 2016 ( <b>Issued</b> )
•	Virtual Split Dictionary for Search Optimization (US)	Dec 2015 ( <b>Issued</b> )
•	Improved Expression of Breastmilk via Automated Methods (US)	Jun 2016 ( <b>Filed</b> )
•	Multi-Dimensional Visual Analytics for Industries (US/India)	Sep 2015 ( <b>Filed</b> )

In-Memory DB Optimization Using Statistical Estimation (IEEE CCEM 2015)
A Cost-Effective Sign Language to Voice Emulation System (IEEE IC3 2015)
Aug 2015 (Published)